one
live like said welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer will we open up with the Ten
Commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep brother
tanzel and God spake all these words
saying I am the Lord thy God which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt
out of the house of bondage thou shall
have no other gods before me thou shall
not make unto thee any Graven image or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above or that is in the earth
beneath or that is in the water under
the Earth thou shall not bow down
thyself to them nor serve them for the
Lord thy God am a jealous God visiting
the iniquities of the fathers upon the
children until the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me and
showing Mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my Commandments
thou shall not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain for the Lord will not
hold him Guiltless that taketh his name
in vain remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy six days shall thy labor and do
all thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God and that
thou shall not do any work thou nor thy
son nor thy daughter thy man's servant
nor thy maid servant nor thy cattle nor
thy stranger that is within thy gates
for six days the Lord made Heaven and
Earth the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day wherefor the
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hollowed it honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee thou shall not kill thou shall not
commit adultery thou shall not steal
thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor thou not cover thy
neighbor's house thou shall not cover
thy neighbor's wife nor his man's
servant nor his ma servant nor his o nor
his ass nor anything that is thy
neighbors we read exod 21-1 17 and may
the Lord have a blessing to the reading
of his words in Jesus name we pray amen
amen so here on question and answer you
can ask us a question and we'll answer
it according to the King James Bible and
if we cannot find the answer we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time the questions we
will not answer are the vague and long
scripture questions as well as questions
of debate we are not here to debate we
are here to spread the true Gospel of
Jesus so please be direct with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible no other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program also keep in mind this is a live
stream so feel free to send in your
questions that pertain to everlasting
life we're just asking that you keep
your questions to a two scripture
maximum but let me introduce you to
family that's on the panel this evening
we we got brother Dre good evening
brother Julius good evening everybody
brother Jerome Grace and peace Brother
tanzel good evening sister Deborah good
evening and we have sister Casey as well
as a guest caller with us and I'm
brother Cornell sister Deborah what is
our first question of the evening
all right our first
question are you there sister on mute
you're on
mute um so can you hear me now correct
all right so the first question is from
time Al Houston and time Al Houston
asked uh why did God call the Persian
king
his messiah in Isaiah 45 verse1 17 this
Cyrus truly worshiped the god of
Israel all right is that Isaiah 45 and
one
yes all right so brother Julius share
some
light uh we going to make a slight
correction uh the question is why did
God call the Persian king Cyrus his
Messiah he didn't call Cyrus his Messiah
he called him his anointed one or his
chosen one we know that Messiah means uh
the anointed one but that really
referred to Jesus so that is a Smith's
literal translation that you're reading
that from let's look at what the Bible
say uh Isaiah 45
And1 thus say the Lord to his anointing
to Cyrus whose right hand I have Holden
to subdue Nations before him and I will
loose and I will loose the loins of
Kings to open before him the two leaves
Gates and the gates shall not be shut so
now the Lord called Cyrus is Anointed
and because Cyrus just like anybody else
does anointed by God you are chosen to
do an assignment let me show you what s
cus was chosen to do back up tzel to the
44th chapter and read verse 27 and 28
th said to the Deep be dry and I will
dry up thy Rivers th said of Cyrus he is
my shepherd He is my what shepherd He is
a Shepherd so go
ahead and shall perform all my pleasures
and what is and what is the Lord's
pleasure why did he choose Cyrus go
ahead even saying to Jerusalem thou
shall be built and to the temple thy
Foundation shall be laid so so if you
read 2 Chronicles 36 all this is backed
up by 2 Chronicles 36 and the Lord
prophesied that Cyrus would be chosen to
free the Jews let them go back and build
the the uh the City Jerusalem and the
temple so that when Jesus came on the
scene he would have a temple to go to so
that is why Cyrus was called the Lord's
anointed because when you are anointed
by God you are chosen to do something
and everybody worships God sooner or
later they all worship God including
Cyrus you can read that in Daniel the
10th chapter on your own but that's the
answer to that I hope that
helped all right thank you for that
brother hope that answer that question
as we move on to our next one uh next
one fire fire says I have talked to many
about the dietary law and they choose to
not
keep it how do we reconcile 1 corini 10
verse
27 which seems to
possibly permit the eating of unclean
unbondable things all right well that is
not possible for those that have the
truth let's go to 1 Corinthians 10 and
verse 27 and the guest caller will take
it from
there first Corinthians 10 and 27 if any
of them that believe not bid you to a
feast and ye be be disposed to go so
whatsoever is set before you eat asking
no questions for conscience
sake the first thing
is you know it's uh uh uh if anybody uh
B you if they don't if they don't
believe then the whole thing is he say
if you'll dispose the goat why should
you be the SW to go and you know that
they don't believe you don't
go because if you're a servant of God
and you got some people that don't
believe in the dietary law and they viid
you to a feast then contrary to what
Paul said here if you should go and they
put food in front of you if you don't
ask him what it is and you eat it then
you going to break God's dietary law
what you going to do you going to break
with God's dietary
law I don't think
so so you going ask him what is
this you have not broken a law if you
say that cuz I don't see nowhere in the
law where the Bible said thou if you go
to a feast don't ask the people what
they put before you to eat it's not in
the law the law said beast you should
eat and Beast you should not eat
going invite you to a feast and you know
they don't keep the dietary law then you
should not be dis how it said dispose to
go you tell them thanks but no thanks
stay at home that's all I have to say
all right hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next
question next question uh Zion
says will the ones that have not been
baptized in Jesus name have the chance
to be baptized in the
wilderness all right so if you have not
been baptized in Jesus name do you have
the chance to be baptized in the
wilderness guess
caller it's not so much as will you have
a chance you will get baptized in the
wilderness or you will not get out of
the wildness let's go to
Ezekiel Ezekiel chapter 20 and and we're
going to start reading this
around around
verse
35 read it when you get there and I will
bring you into the Wilderness of the
people and there would I plead with you
face to face like as I pleaded with your
fathers in the wilderness of the land of
Egypt so would I plead with you sayth
the Lord God and I will cause you to
pass under the rod and I will bring you
into the bond of the Covenant and I will
Purge out now when he said I'm going
call call your p on the rod and I'm
bring you into the bond of the
Covenant we're going to show you what
that is later on how you come into the
bond of the Covenant but uh uh but if
you will refuse to come into the bond of
the Covenant let's see what's going to
happen keep reading I will Purge out
from among you the rebels and them that
transgress against me I will bring them
forth out of the country where they
sourn and they shall not enter into the
land of Israel and ye shall know that I
am the
Lord so now if you refuse to come into
the bond of the Covenant then you will
not get into the land so let's go and
look at this and how do you come into
the bond of the Covenant let's go into
Galatians the thir
chapter read verse
26 to
29 gelati chapter
[Music]
3 for ye are all the children of God by
faith in Christ Jesus for as many for as
many of you as have been baptized into
Christ have put on Christ there is
neither Jew nor Greek
there is neither Bond nor free there is
neither male nor female for ye are all
one in Christ
Jesus and if you be Christ then are ye
Abraham's seed and HS according to the
promise now the Covenant was made with
Abraham and his seed so in order for you
come Abraham seed then and and and come
out the b of the Covenant you have to be
C baptized in the name of Jesus
and if you be Christ then are you
Abraham seed but if you don't get
baptized you get purged in the
wilderness you don't get to the promised
land
right so you must be baptized if you're
baptized before good but if you're not
when you get there you will be baptized
that's why he said I'm going plead with
you face to face and I'm going bring you
into the bond of the Covenant and you go
that no I don't want to be baptized in
the name of JC then you die right there
in the wilderness
you're not an opportunity it's a
must that's all that's right you going
do it his way or you ain't gonna have no
way simple as
that all right hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question moving on Stephen googus asks
are there any PR uh precepts in the
Bible of Ephesians 4 verse2
26 getting angry and not sinning and and
not holding on to
anger sure there's uh precepts all
throughout the Bible sometime anger can
get you in trouble if it's not
controlled and when you say the word
precept precept is a rule designed to
regulate or change your thoughts or
actions now let's go on that Ephesians 4
that they asked about ephes
four and this is where the Lord is
saying hey he know that we can get angry
because we in this body but don't sin
while you
are angry and when the sun go down it's
all over got to put that anger aside and
thank God for another day all right
Ephesians 4 and pick it up at that verse
23 because the precept part is to be
renewed in your mind and regulate your
change or your thoughts go ahead and be
renewed in the spirit of your mind uhhuh
that you put on the new man which after
God has created in righteousness and
true Holiness yes wherefore putting away
lying speaking every man truth with his
neighbor for we are members one of
another that's right but be ye angry and
sin not and let not the sun go down upon
your wrath the Lord say hey he said we
can yeah you can be angry but inside
that anger you're not supposed to commit
any sin and then once the sun go down
hey you put that aside and you move on
to another day now let's go into uh
Ecclesiastes the 7 chapter Ecclesiastes
7 because this is going to let us know
how we have to be wise on anger because
it can get you in trouble many a brother
is in deep trouble because his anger or
sister because the anger got the best of
them for that moment Ecclesiastes 7 and
read one verse n for me and then we go
to uh
Proverbs go ahead brother be not Hasty
in thy Spirit to be angry for anger
rested in the bosom of fools so don't be
Hasty in thy Spirit to get angry some
people every little thing upset them
they mad they ready to fight ready ready
to raise a lot of sand but the Lord say
don't be hasty don't be quick to get
angry because in your spirit hey it can
make you do some foolish things turn
over to Proverbs
14 Proverbs the 14th
chapter because hey even with our
children sometime should let them know
hey it's okay to get angry but um don't
uh let that get you in trouble watch
that mouth of yours Proverbs 14
and pick it up at that verse 17 and
that'll be it one verse go
ahead he that is soon angry D foolishly
and a man of wicked devices is hated so
he does soon angry quick to get angry
everything is wrong make him mad and
upset hey he go deal foolishly and he
may end up paying a price that he can't
afford so that question about the
precepts there's more but there go a
couple right there and uh
use that wisdom and knowledge to your
life that's all I
get all right we hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one
our next one he also asked in Genesis 2
vers 19 and 20 Adam named the animals
does this mean that Adam was here on
Earth before the animals since Adam
named them or or were the animals here
first and nameless before Adam named
them all right let's go to Genesis 2
read that 19 and 20 and the guest caller
take it from
there okay Genesis 2:9 and 20 and out of
the ground the Lord God form every beast
of the field and every fou of the air
and brought them unto Adam to see what
he would call them and whatsoever Adam
called every living creature that was an
angel
thereof Adam gave names to all cattle
and to the fowls of the air and to every
beast of the field but for Adam there
was not found a help meat for
him now the who thing is whoever asked
this question all he had to do was back
up one verse and it would have answered
itself Verse 18 what's it say and the
Lord God said is not it is not good that
man should be alone I will make him a
help me for
him it is not good that man should be
alone that mean it wasn't nobody there
was
it I will make a help meat for
him then what happened after that go
ahead and out of the ground the Lord God
formed every beast of the field and
every foul of the air and brought them
unto Adam to see what he would call them
and whato Adam called every living
creature that was the name thereof
uhhuh and Adam gave Nam to all cattle
and to the fouls of the air and to every
beast of the field but for Adam there
was not found a help meat for him now
remember how this started out it is not
good for man to be alone
right I will find a help meat which is
suitable then he created all the animals
and once he got through with the animals
it still he still didn't have a help
that was suitable to man
then he put man uh Adam to sleep and
took a rib and made the
woman so Adam was here before every all
of them the 18th verse let it know when
it is not good for man to be alone so
you going to someone make him a help
that's suitable of him first he created
the animals but they weren suitable so
he calleda him to have a deep sleep and
he brought forth the
woman the r and made a woman out of it
now that was suitable for
him so yeah he created animals after
Adam just like Eve come after
Adam that's all I have to say all right
moving on to our next question next
question mark Ash
asss during the
transatlantic slave trade the ships
would drop off slaves at the ports in
South America America and the
Caribbean so why wouldn't they be
considered Israelites if they were the
same as the black people coming to
America all right so why would that be
the case brother
Jerome well the people that was on those
uh slave ships that were dropped off in
the Caribbeans and the South uh South
America they were isra
isites but you got you got other nations
of people that don't fit all of the
curses that's spoken of in Deuteronomy
28th chapter he only put those curses on
the children of Israel he didn't put
them on any other Nation okay so let's
go to this uh Amos 3 uh let's go to Amos
3 verse 1 and two
Amos chapter 3 verse 1 and two and we
going to go to Deuteronomy 28 after that
tanel okay Amos 31
and2 hear this word that the Lord has
spoken against you oh children of
Israel against the whole family which I
brought up from the land of Egypt saying
ye only have I known of all the families
of the earth therefore I will punish you
for all your
iniquities yeah
and everybody know that don't happen to
nobody but the socalled Nigro everybody
know that right okay so uh Deuteronomy
28 go there and read verse 45 and
46 oh all these curses shall come upon
thee and shall pursue thee and overtake
thee till thou be destroyed because thou
hearken is not unto the voice of the
Lord thy God to keep his Commandments
and his statutes which he command thee
and they shall be upon thee for a sign
and for a wonder and upon thy seed
forever yeah say it gonna be a it's
going to be a
sign that these are the people to Israel
no matter how mixed up you might get
about feel about some other people look
at all these signs and see who they
point to and they point to one nation
that's the children of Israel right
nobody else that's all I got if anybody
want to ask something yeah you know what
make you think people in in uh uh that
that you didn't have Israelites dropped
off in in uh uh uh Central and South
America those were black people too
that's right it's all that simple you
know the Lord told you that he's going
to scatter us into Every Nation Under
the Sun so you got Israelites in Mexico
but they black Puerto Rica but they
black then you look at the Asian they
black then look at the fan
Island you got blacks there but they
wasn't but they wern't ruled and they
didn't go there on their own they was
all brought there as slaves so the
biggest uh thing you have to find out
who was brought here as slaves in the H
of the ship and sold as male and female
slaves
who was it and you'll find out it was
all
black
yeah yeah don't have to say all right
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one next one Aaron
ronell says I am 49 can I get baptized
and still minister God's word 49 want to
get baptized and be a minister for God's
word guess caller
well you got to get baptized anyway
before you do any kind of ministry but
the lord gave you from 30 to 50 through
now if you are you better Hur up and get
baptized and start trying to teach
quickly and get into it at the last
minute but the Lord said from 30 to 50
so you still got another year left get
busy brother all I have to say yeah all
right moving on to our next question
next question uh Troy Barber
asks is it against the law
or bad to celebrate Valentine's or
acknowledge the day in any
capacity someone said it was wrong and
sent me this
verse uh Hebrews 13 verse4 Mary which is
Honorable in all in the bad unile but
whor mongers and adulterers God will
judge Valentine's and that scripture in
the same sentence gu
caller what that scripture don't have
nothing to do with Valentine's
Day Valentine's Day started is started
under under the uh uh uh uh Catholic
church and it was named after St
Valentine the scriptures she the use
which should have been in the
Commandment the Lord said thou shall
have no other God before me
right and anybody that celebrates St
Valentine's Day is dealing with a pagan
God it's all that simple and there
nowhere in the Bible so you gave they
gave you the wrong scripture they should
have read the Commandment thou sh have
no other go before
me got nothing to do with love love is
the Fulfillment of the
law right
right that's all I have to say all right
hope that answers your question as we
move on to our next question next one
micia cure asked in Revelation 1
verse1 what is the Lord's day in this
verse also are there any Ang angs are
there any female
angels all right brother Julius share
some light let's go tzel quickly
Revelation 1
and10 when you get it go ahead brother I
was in the spirit on the Lord's day and
heard behind me a great voice as of a
trumpet now the Lord's day is a period
of time when the Lord begin to intervene
in the Affairs of men and begin to take
over the kingdoms of this world okay
let's let's give you an example of what
happens on the Lord day and what
announces the Lord's day this has
nothing to do with Sunday this is a
period of time in Prophecy let's go to
Revelation the 6th
chapter we're going to read quick tanzel
Revelation 6 I want you to start reading
at verse 12 and then we going to skip to
14 now be when he had opened the six
seal and low there was a great
earthquake and the son became black as
saclo of hair and the moon became as
blood now these are the signs that
announces the day of the Lord skip down
to verse 14 what else happens you gonna
see this go ahead and the heaven
departed as a scroll when it is rolled
together and every mountain and Island
were removed out of their places and the
book say all the men fled and the armies
and everything and hide skip down to
verse 16 and
continue and said to the mouths and
rocks fall on us and hide us from the
face of him that sth on the throne and
from the Wrath of the Lamb this is Jesus
why verse 17 for the great day of his
wrath is come and who shall be able to
stand why they nobody gonna be able to
stand except those that stand with Jesus
last place Zechariah the 14th chapter
Zechariah 14th chapter yes sir Zechariah
14 we got to read 1 to4 we got to read
quick Zechariah 14 1-4 go ahead behold
the day of the Lord come when th behold
what comes the day of the Lord the day
of the Lord It's the period of time when
the Lord begin to take over the kingdoms
of this world go ahead brother and thy
spoil shall be divided in the midst of
Thee I will gather all nations against
Jerusalem to battle and the city shall
be taken and the houses RI rifled and
the women rabbit and half of the Cities
shall go forth to captivity and the
residue of the people shall not be cut
off from the city then shall the Lord go
forth and fight against those Nations as
when he fought in the day of battle go
ahead brother his feet shall stand in
that day upon the Mount of olive which
is before Jerusalem on the East and the
Mount of olive shall cleave in the midst
thereof towards the east and towards the
west and there should be a very great
valley half of the mount shall remove
toward the North and half of it towards
the South so now who comeing with the
Lord when he come one more verse and ye
shall flee to the Valley of the the
mountain for the Valley of the mountain
shall reach into Asel yet ye shall flee
like as he fled from before the
earthquake in the days of Uzziah king of
Judah and the Lord my God shall come and
all the saints with thee so this is
where the Lord he GNA get these
resurrect resurrected resurrect
resurrected Saints from the grave meet
the Lord in the Clouds of the air and
those who are uh chain that is coming
meet the Lord in the air we all come
back to the Earth and we help the Lord
with this thing and this right here is
called the day of the Lord which is a
Thousand-Year period so John saw the
Lord uh projected John in his mind into
the future and showed him his return to
the second part of your question there
are no females Angels written or
listed they don't exist according to
what we read in the
Bible that's all I got
Corel right
is one other one other thing I think is
Joel two
one third second or third chapter where
it said the deal the de of the Lord
cometh cruel and full of
Wrath that's Isaiah uh 13 I
think day of the Lord cometh cruel and
full of Wrath yeah uh uh 13 and9 behold
the day of the Lord coming crew both
with r and fierce anger that one yeah to
lay the land desolate and he shall
destroy the Sinners thereof out of
it no what I'm talking about I think is
than Joel I just want to let you know
that this day is a cruel day and full of
the Wrath of the
Lord youbody look for jeel right quick
see
if I got uh Joel to uh you want kick it
off you me start at verse one
yeah blow ye the trumpet in Zion the
sound and in my Holy Mountain and all
that happen the land tremble for the day
of the Lord cometh for it is not for it
is night at hand a day of darkness and
of gloominess a day of clouds and thick
Darkness as a morning spread upon the
mountains a great
people
huh that's what I was looking at to let
you know this day of the Lord couldn't
be uh uh talking about a regular day
just like Julius say as a time period
has come cruel a day of darkness and
Wrath you read all of that and you can
read Joel too uh where he say a day of
darkness and of gloominess a day of
clouds thick
darkness and he gon to hurt the people
on this Earth sisters and
brothers right so that's the day when
the Lord show up and and he going to
show up killing people tell you that he
going to fill the place with dead
bodies the and the slain of the Lord
going to be from one end of the Earth to
the other so they talking about hey
that's talking about the time period
starting when the heaven Ru back like a
scroll like J Jus read that's all I have
to say thank you gu call all right hope
that answers your question as we move on
to our next moving on Christy Watson
asked what is taking the Lord's God name
in vain example oh my God for God's sake
Etc all right Jerome what you
got yes it's much much deeper than that
um examples of taking the lord's name in
vain uh especially if you claiming to be
his servant is to break his law you know
so now let's let's go take some looks at
that let's go to uh Romans 2 Romans two
yeah and read verse 33 I'm sorry Romans
2 read verse 23 and 24 and then we going
to go to uh Proverbs after
that okay Romans 2 uh 23 and 24 yes thou
that makest thy boast of the law through
breaking the law dishonor thou God for
the name of God is blasing among the
Gentiles through you as it is
written yeah so boasting about you a
servant or Israelite or whatever but you
breaking his law you taking his name in
vain uh let's go to proverbs
30 and read verse 8
and9 when you did it go ahead and read
remove far from me vanity and lies give
me neither poverty nor riches feed the
with food convenient for me lest I be fo
and deny thee and say who is the Lord or
lest I be poor and still and take the
name of my God in vain yeah so this he
still which is one of the things we are
not to do according to the Commandment
of God right and if we do we taking his
name in vain especially if you call
yourself a servant of the Lord that's
all I got
on and and even Jerome that um you hear
people sometimes say Jesus then they
bring a curse word after that you know
see that in the movies and everywhere
they should delete that from their
vocabulary as well yeah but the direct
answer that question is is when you
break his law yeah that's why Solomon
said don't give me too little unless I
steal and take the name of of the Lord
in vain so you break his law ain't no
need to calling on his
name CU you're calling on it for nothing
that's what in vain mean okay all right
hope that answers your question next
question next question most love ask why
does the devil constantly try to destroy
the ones that's keeping the laws
wouldn't it be easier to tempt the ones
that's not keeping the
Commandment all right brother Dre what
you say yeah he want both of them he
want the ones that's not he want the
ones that is but the ones that's not
more than likely he got a hold on them
already let's go to uh John 10 and we
going to read verse 10 and we got one
other place John 10 verse
10 the thief cometh not was you ready
for me yes sir go ahead the thief cometh
not for for to steal and to kill and to
destroy I am come that they might have
life and that they might have it more
abundantly so that's what the thief came
to do he came to kill steal and Destroy
but let's go over to Revelation 12 now
Revelation
12 this is who he
want revelation 12 and I want you to
read verse
13 and we going to
skip go ahead and when the dragon saw
that he was cast into the Earth he
persecuted the woman which brought forth
The Man Child yeah so he persecuted the
woman which brought forth The Man Child
and that is Israel skip down to verse 17
go ahead and the dragon was RO with the
woman and went to make war with the
remnant of her seed which keep the
Commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus
Christ yeah so to identify who that
dragon is read verse nine go
ahead and the Great Dragon was cast out
that old serpent called the devil and
Satan was deceiving the whole world he
was cast out to the Earth and his angels
were cast out with him and he is WTH
with the woman and he went to make war
with the remnant of her seed who keep
the Commandments of God so you can
expect that but like told the serpent
when he came to him man does not live by
bread alone but by every word that
proceeds out of the mouth of God man
live and that is your Weaponry that's
right against the Devil with I hope that
helped all right thank you for that
brother as we move on to our next
question moving on Israel by Blood
Brandon
says I watch iog Riverdale campus every
satday and I wanted to know how do I
call in and get H and get a shout out
during the start of the Sabbath day
lesson
well if if you're able to to travel the
distance come and pay us a visit we'll
be glad to see your face in the place
but if not then you just call 708
39213 20 and uh someone will answer the
line for you and ask you who you are and
where you from and that's how you're
able to call in that's all I
got as we move on to our next question
next question uh credit account ask uh
was Daniel a
unit uh Bible doesn't doesn't say that
that Daniel was a unit that I've read
but the definition of a unit can be
someone born with a a defect in a genor
area or had a surgical procedure done or
even someone who just decides to be
civan they even called them a unit too
so it doesn't say in the Bible that uh
that I read that Daniel was a unit
that's all I
get you know as we
move is it was it in what that Daniel
just said that he prophesied that
morning and the Lord said I take away
the desire of your eyes and that even
that his wife died that was Ezekiel
Ezekiel that was Ezekiel that was
Ezekiel oh okay then all right
now we don't know whether Daniel was was
a unic or not
there
okay moving on to our next question
moving on uh step goog asked is there
anything in the Bible of people playing
sports or games of any kind anywhere in
the Bible are people playing sports and
having a little fun of any kind brother
Julius we don't have much on that aspect
but we do have a whole lot about running
races let's go to First Corinthians the
nth chapter I'm sure it they did because
there's nothing new up under the sun
just call it a different name today
let's go to First Corinthians the n9th
chapter 1 Corinthians chapter
9 and when you get it tangel read verse
know ye not that they which run in a
race run all but one receiveth the prize
so run we have so we have some foot
races going on don't
we yeah you running you running it's
just like the Olympics you running track
you doing field they had those things in
the ancient days in Greece they had the
Olympics so all nations had their way of
entertainment and sports the Romans did
those kind of things in their colise
just because everything thing is not
listed don't mean it don't exist but he
said know ye not that they which run the
race run all but one receiveth the prize
go ahead tzel and every man that
striveth for the matter is temporal in
all
things now they do it to obtain the
corruptible crime but we are
Incorruptible give me one more I
therefore so run not as uncertainly so
fight I but not as one that beateth the
air so Paul is working out showing you
how to work out your salvation and
seeking the kingdom of God first that's
the greatest race you could run right
there but in the meantime yes they did
have uh uh uh games and they had races
and competitions of those
sort based on the scriptures that we can
read Psalm the 19th Chapter verse 5 is
another one ecclesiast 2 Timothy 4 and
7even he said I fought a good fight so
they that I'm sure they had sparring and
everything there's nothing new up under
the sun that's the best I can answer
that right all right thank you for that
brother as we move on to our next
question we're going into new territory
sister de yes we are uh we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday February the
2025 I chuck woo ask is it okay to have
a memorial service for a Lov one if not
are there scriptures you can refer me
to it's okay to have a memorial service
for a loved one which uh means to keep
in memory let's go into a memorial unto
God and read one which there are many
Psalms 135 let's go there Psalms
135 and when you get there brother pick
it up at that verse
three because the Lord have a lot of
stuff in here all his feast days he
wants to keep a lot of stuff in Memorial
to
him
Psalm okay praise the Lord for the Lord
is good sing praises unto his name for
it is
Pleasant goad for the Lord have chosen
Jacob unto himself and Israel for his
peculiar
treasure that the Lord is great and that
our Lord is above all gods skip down
brother to verse eight and go
ahead who smok the first born of Egypt
both of man and Beast Lord even want us
to keep that in memory the great works
he did when he brought us out of Egypt
skip down to verse
10 who spoke great Nations and slew
Mighty Kings even gave us some of their
lands skip down and read 12 and 13 and
gave their lands for an inheritance and
inherited unto Israel his people uhhuh
thy name oh Lord endure forever and thy
Memorial oh Lord throughout all
generation yes and all those great works
the Lord want us to keep that in memory
and a memorial unto him now let's go and
deal with a sister that something also
is a memorial unto her Matthew the 26th
chapter Matthew
26 cuz Memorial is just keeping memory
of and we see too much of that in the
community with the balloon releases and
people Gathering you know having
memorials for they loved ones who have
passed Matthew 26 and let's pick it up
at that verse 6 go
ahead now when Jesus was in Bethany in
the house of Simon the leop there came
unto him a woman having an alabaster box
of very precious ointment and poured on
his head as he said at meat mhm when the
disciples saw it they had indignation
saying to what purpose is this waste so
this lady was coming here to basically
anoint Jesus with the alabaster box of
precious ointment skip down read 12 and
13 for in that she have poured his
ointment on my body she did it for my
burial uhhuh I say unto you where soever
this gospel shall be preached in the
whole world there shall also this that
that this woman have done be told for
Memorial of her right so that was a
memorial piece that when she went to
anoint the body of Jesus and hey he said
she did it for my burial that that will
be told throughout generations and we
telling it right now so yeah you can
have a memorial for your loved ones that
have passed that's all I
got all right hope that answered your
question next question next question
Stephen gas asked in Zechariah 11 ver8
what does it mean when it says they
serve for one month didn't these
Shepherds or king of Israel serve longer
than one month so brother Jerome shed
some light on this one month
concept yeah that that that um one month
actually symbolizes a
lot uh it actually simple uh symbolizes
30 years actually I think that third
that one month symbolized that and they
served actually uh they didn't serve 30
years all together between the three of
them okay so um let's go read that verse
you gave
though Zechariah 11 and8 yeah 118
three Shepherds also I cut off in one
month my soul loathed them and their
souls also up horded
me yeah so between the three of them the
last three kings uh the Israel had um
let's go read about them um let's go to
2 Chronicles chapter
36 and it'll give you the amount of
years that all the last three kings
actually reain and it it's going to be
under 30 years all together okay so go
to uh the fifth verse second chronicles
36 read verse 5 then skip to
n and jeh was 25 years old when he began
to Reign and he reigned 11 years in
Jerusalem and he did that which was evil
in the sight of the Lord his God uhhuh
skip to verse n jeim was eight years old
when he began reigned and he reigned
three months and 10 days in Jerusalem
and he did that which was evil in the
sight of the Lord and the last king
zedekiah read verse 11 zedekiah was and0
years old when he began to Reign and he
reigned 11 years in
Jerusalem yeah so that was actually 22
years and three months and 10 days all
together right they didn't all together
they didn't rule 30 years and that's
what that one month mean that's all I
got
on all right thank you for that as we
move on to our next question next
question about the father's business
asked is Paul implying that no man
should have long hair according to 1
Corinthians 11
verse4 brother Dre what you
say no Paul is telling you about nature
and and naturally speaking but let's go
to 1 Corinthians
11:14 we read that verse and then we'll
read verse 16 because prior to this it
tells you about a man covering his head
and a woman woman a man uncovering his
head and a woman covering her head
because of the Angels but verse 14 go
ahead brother do have not even nature is
self teach you that if a man have long
hair it is a shame unto him so he's
saying do this do nature teach you this
but skip down and read verse 16 go ahead
but if any man seem to be
contentious we have no such custom
neither the Churches of God we don't
have a this custom that if a man have
long
hair you know it's it it don't be
contentious about it because we don't
have that custom and when you look at it
Absalon had long hair Samson had long
hair but let's let's go look at Absalon
let's go to 2 Samuel 14 and we just
going to read verse
26 2 Samuel 14 and
26 read it when you get
there and when he pulled his head for it
was at every year end that he pulled it
he pulled it because the hair was heavy
on him therefore he ped it he weighed
the hair of his head at 200 shekel after
the king's weight so the weight of 200
shekel I look that up and that is five
pound so that was five pounds of hair
Absalon had long hair Samson had long
hair he was a
Nazarite and that in terms of custom no
nature you know you may mistake a man
for a woman having long hair but that
might be a shame to him but other than
that no no shame that's all I
got all right thank you for that brother
hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next question next
question just no chill at is Isaiah
58: 13 and 14 telling us not to call the
Sabbath a delight or is it telling us to
enjoy God's Sabbath by keeping it it's
telling you the the latter part the
second part is telling you to enjoy
God's Sabbath and keep it let's go to
Isaiah
58 Isaiah
58 and let's pick it up at that verse 13
because the Lord is telling us to turn
our foot toward the Sabbath day and turn
it away from doing your own pleasure go
ahead
brother if thou turn away thy foot from
the Sabbath from doing thy pleasure on
my holy day and call the Sabbath of
delight the holy of the Lord honorable
and shall honor him not doing thy own
ways nor finding their own pleasure nor
speaking thy own words so you see here
that the Lord is telling us that we
supposed to call the Sabbath day a
delight because it's a blessing and
those of us that know it's even for a
sign to come when the Lord is going to
hey even have his day of rest for us but
go ahead then shall thou Delight thyself
in the Lord and I will cause thee to
ride upon the high places of the earth
and feed thee with the heritance of
Jacob thy father for the mouth of the
Lord have spoken it yes because the Lord
is letting us know that we are supposed
supposed to call a Sabbath a delight
holy unto the Lord supposed to keep it
the way he say keep it it's supposed to
be honorable for us we supposed to honor
him and not do our own ways nor finding
our own Pleasures you got six days to do
all of that but on this day the Lord
wants you to focus all your attention on
him his day that you may serve him with
all your heart and get strength to serve
him all week all the way until his
return that's all I
got hope that answered your question as
we move on to our next one moving on
desmine Marshall asks in Matthew 10
verse 16 in regards to being as wise as
a serpent and harmless as a dove in the
midst of wolves how can I apply this
scripture to my personal daily life all
right why don't we go there Matthews 10
and
16 and they want to know how do they
apply that scripture unto they daily
life and the guest caller would take it
from
there behold I send you forth as sheep
in the midst of wolves be ye therefore
wise as serpents and harmless as
dogs but when he tell you be wise and
ser that's when you open your mouth know
what you you're talking about it Humes
is D be humble when you're talking even
when you're correcting somebody when
they
wrong so you know because people get
some wisdom and they have some
understanding they get real puffed up
and they talk to people disrespectful
and try and make them look bad but no if
you going to talk about a subject know
what you're talking about that's wise is
a servant but then when you talk to him
talk to them humbly even if they're
wrong you can tell them that they're
wrong without snapping on them without
without making them uh uh uh uh feel
bad just tell them humbly if you wise
you going to know what you're talking
about if and if you're gentle you're
going to be humble that's all they
saying know what you're talking about
and be humble when you talk about it all
I have to say yeah all right hope that
answered your question next question
with the time check uh yes the time is
uh
8:29 Valencia uh says can you explain 2
corini 5 verse 24 uh brother Cornell all
right well sister Valencia we have no 2
Corinthians 5 and 24 so we asking you if
you could please resubmit your question
and we'll try and address it at at that
time moving on to our next question
moving on uh Marsh a uh says I know that
Israel is supposed to teach the other
nations but was Simon the Canaanite the
Apostle of Jesus ah
hamite hence Matthew 10 verse4 and Mark
3 Verse
18 all ra what you
say uh let's go read those verses um
Matthews 104 and Mark 3
and18 Matthew 10 and4 Simon the canite
and Judas es scariot who also betrayed
him okay and Mark 3
and18 and Andrew and Phillip and
Bartholomew and Matthew and Thomas and
James the son of alaus and
dadas and Simon the
Canaanite okay um no Simon was
100% Israelite you know of the land of
Canaan remember
he you had Canaanites in that land that
was before Israel came into that land
remember the hamites are the original
Canaanites you know of of the people of
Canaan the he ties the jebusites them
people okay all right but uh no Simon
was an Israelite and plus um lord said I
was sent to the lost sheep of the House
of Israel he was he wasn't sent to
nobody else and then he sent his
disciples I mean his his Apostles he
sent them to the other
nations okay but the Lord he was only
sent to the lost sheep cuz he had to get
his teachers he had to get his priest
Nation ready the Jews at that time he
had to get them ready so they can teach
it and teach it right right once he got
them right then he sent them into all
the world you know but uh let's go to uh
Matthews 15 Read verse
22 and then we going to go to Exodus 23
after that
tanel and the woman um and behold a
woman of Canaan came out of the same
coast and Cried unto him saying have
mercy on me oh Lord thou son of David my
daughter is grievously vexed with the
devil all right now this woman right
here see was an
Israelite
okay and if you go to Exodus it it'll
kind of break down that the hamites was
in that land before Israel was the Lord
G took the land from the hamites and
gave it to Israel
okay so now go ahead read verse 23-
24 but he answered her not a word and
the disciples came and besought him
saying send her away for she crith after
us but he answered and said I am not
sent but unto the lost sheep of the
House of Israel yeah and he came and he
picked 12 Apostles and every one of them
were Israelites right that's all I got
wait a minute keep reading
okay then came she and worshiped him
saying Lord help me but he answered and
said it is not me to take the children's
bread and cast it to a dog to
dogs and she said truth Lord yet the
dogs eat of the crumbs which fallen from
their master's
table he actually called that canite
woman a dog
right and then she got with humble said
well the dog of the crumbs of the
master's table then keep reading what he
say then Jesus answered and said unto
her oh woman great is thy faith be it
unto thee even as thou will and her
daughter was made whole from that very
hour okay cuz he wouldn't talk to her at
first then call the woman a dog but
because she had was was humble and and
uh uh uh and and believe that he could
do it then he let he healed Accord her
daughter according to his faith so how
is he going to run around with the
people an
apostle and he's a Canaanite and he just
called this woman a dog a Canaanite
[Music]
woman once again too the Lord said
Israel is uh is his priest nobody
else that's all I have to
say all right thank you for that as we
move on to our next question
moving on Glenn Sirus
says these last few days I have been
dealing with anxiety
issues any scriptures to help with
feeling this way I often find myself
overthinking and worrying about what the
future is going to
be all right brother julus bring a
little calm with the scriptures yes sir
let's let's do that let's do that let
let me show you you something uh uh uh
brothers and
sister let's go to Philippians the 4th
chapter Philippians the 4th chapter
let's do this uh uh tzel Philippians
chapter 4 because Jesus said something
and the disciples said something
concerning the things and all the thing
that's going on in the world that's
going to Vex our spirit Philippians 4
pick it up at verse 6 and
7 go
yeah be careful for nothing but in
everything by prayer and supplication
with Thanksgiving let your request be
made known unto God now he said don't
worry about this stuff be thankful now
that's why you get to the Israel of God
and you pick this Bible up it is the
good news and it's exciting and it is a
blessing to understand what is going on
so that you don't have to worry so when
it come you your faith is in Jesus
Christ and that gives you great comfort
let's go let's go to John
16 John 16 and we going to read because
this depression this anxiety can lead to
depression sisters and brothers than
John
16-33 with everything that's going on in
the world our only consolation is in the
word of God St John 16 and just read
verse 33 T when you get it go ahead
brother these things I have spoken unto
you that in me ye might have peace but
in the world ye shall have tribulation
will be of good cheer I have overcome
the world that's why Jesus told you in
Matthew the 24th chapter and Luke the
21st chapter he that endureth until the
end the same shall be saved sisters and
brothers but your faith got to be in
Jesus Christ and in him you could have
peace no matter what's going on in the
world you could have peace let's do uh
let's do first Peter
5 1 Peter 5 we got a lot of scriptures
on there that's why you read this Bible
because it is the only thing that can
carry you through these times 1 Peter 5
read verse 6 look what we got to do
though humble yourselves therefore under
the mighty hand of God yes that he may
exalt you in due time yeah casting all
your care upon him for he care for you
the Lord know what you going through
sister and brothers he know exactly what
you're going through but read the Psalms
read the Psalms the David said I've been
young and I'm old I've never seen the
righteous forsaken nor seed beg and
bread he going to take care of you just
believe in him finish it up brother go
ahead be sober and be vigilant because
your adversary the devil as a roaring
lion walth about seeking whom he may
devour and he wants to devour you with
the thing that's going on in the world
this is his world so he knows how to use
these things to Beast go ahead whom
resist steadfast in the faith knowing
that the same afflictions are and your
brethren that are in the world so you
are not the only one each and every last
one of us that profess to be Servants of
God the Lord told you that you're going
to have
tribulations he said but be a good cheer
I have overcome his example is our
example so that we may have the faith no
matter what just be right pray and the
Lord said the angel of the Lord encamp
around by them that fear Him and keep
his Commandments get to an Israel of God
put on you some lessons and go and and
and just enjoy take take notes and don't
let Satan bring you down he wants to
kill still and Destroy but the Lord say
I came that you might have life Cornell
that's all I got yes sir in that
Philippians 4 when you want that six and
seven we didn't read seven but it say in
the peace of God which Pass of All
understanding shall keep your hearts and
Minds through Christ Jesus thank you
brother because in him sisters and
brothers we have peace and if he be with
you who can be against you nobody that
matters amen yes sir all right brother
thank you for that as we move on to our
next question moving on he oami as are
sabath followed by new moons and kep on
every seven day that the new Moon fell
on
in that month instead of every Saturday
Ezekiel 46 verse1 and three and Isaiah
66 verse 23 is
given all right so when we go to Ezekiel
46 And1 they actually got 46 and3 also
and then Isaiah 66 and 23 and they want
to know about the moons and the Sabbath
and the guest caller share some light
from there
Ezekiel 46
1-3 one and
three thus say the Lord God the Gate of
the inner court that lookth toward the
East shall be shut in the six working
days but on the Sabbath it shall be open
and in the day of the new moon it shall
be
open likewise the people of the land
shall worship at the door of this gate
before the Lord in the sabbaths and in
the new
moons okay you know uh the Lord when you
said the new moons Lord not telling you
to worship the moon the Lord is against
worshiping the elements of heaven when
he talking about the new moon these
talking about the high days right you
know like you come up you know like the
feast days and all that that's why you
have to find out uh uh when the new moon
come up then you have to count to get
certain feast days like uh the 14 day of
the Passover that's the first month then
the 15th day is the Feast of unel
bread but the people but this question
here derived from people that say that
every time you have a new moon that's
the beginning of a new
week if that's the case then you cannot
obey what God say let me show you what
I'm talking
about let's go and and see
what was first the day of the Moon let's
go into Genesis the 1 chapter and read
verses 13-
19 Genesis 13 and
uhhuh and the evening and morning was
the third
day and
God huh
read 1 you said read 13 through 19
right uh uh yeah go ahead and the
evening and the morning were the third
day and God said let there be lights in
the firment of Heaven to divide the day
from the night let them be for signs and
for season and for days and years and
let them be for lights in the firmament
of the heaven to give light upon the
Earth and it was so and God made two
great lights the greater light to the
day and the light to rule the night he
made the Stars also and God set them in
the firment of the heaven to give light
upon the Earth and to rule over the over
the day and over the night and to divide
the light from the darkness and God saw
that it was good in the evening and the
morning was the fourth day now look the
L light is talk about the Moon the Moon
was created on the fourth day the first
second and third day you didn't have no
moon
so if you needed a new moon to start
today at that time we never would have
had a day because the day the day the
moon was created on the day not a day on
the moon I want to show you something
something else let's go into
Exodus the 20th
chapter and we're going to start at
verse we're going to read verse one then
we're going to skip down and read verse
8 and 10
8-10 Exodus
21 20 and verse one and uh read verses
and after that 8 and
10 and God spake all these words
saying remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy six days shall thou lay men do
all thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God and that
thou shall not do any work thou nor th
son nor that daughter thy man servant
nor that Ma servant nor thaty cattle nor
th stranger that's within thy
Gates so now if the new Moon shows up on
the third day so Wednesday and you start
to count all over you going to get you
going to uhh mess up the seven day cycle
right now you won't be able to remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy because
you done messed up the cycle
we have another Commandment that God
gave us to do and this is the last place
let's go to Leviticus the 23
chapter we're going to read 9-
11 and 15 and
16 and the Lord SP to Moses saying
speaking to the children of Israel and
saying unto them when ye be come into
the land which I give unto you ye shall
reap the Harvest thereof he shall bring
a sheep of the first fruit of your
Harvest unto the priest and he shall
wave the Sheep before the Lord to be
accepted for you and on the tomorrow
after the Sabbath the priest shall
waven skri
now verse
15 and ye shall count unto you from the
tomorrow after the Sabbath from the day
that ye brought the sheep of the wave
offering seven sabbaths shall be
complete
even until tomorrow after the seven
Sabbath shall be numbered 50 days and ye
shall offer a new meat offering unto the
Lord now that's the day of Pentecost you
will never put together 50
days
because somewhere in between the new
moon going to show up on one on a day
other than the first day of that week so
when the new moon show up you got to
start your count all over again so by
keeping uh St new month with the new
moon about I means to St new
week on the first day with the first day
of the new moon you're going to break
two Commandments that God gave you one
of them is to remember the Sabbath day
to keep it holy you can't because you
done mess it up by breaking the cycle
and then the Lord said you keep the day
of Pentecost which is 50 days you can't
because you cannot go 50 days without
the new moon showing up on a day other
than the first day of the
week that's all I have to
say all right that's some good light
there as we move on to our next question
moving on next question barer still asks
in Deuteronomy 4 ver
41-43 did Jesus put Moses back to heavy
duty work after the children of Israel
cross over into the promised
land brother
Jerome now let's go read those verses
Deuteronomy 4:
41-43 then Moses served three cities on
the side Jordan towards the sunrising
sever three cities on the side Jordan
that the slave might flee thither which
stood which should kill his neighbor
unawares and hated him not in time pass
and that fleeing unto one of these
cities he might live namly beat bezer in
the wilderness in the plain country of
the reubenites and rayar and Gilead of
the gadites and golad and bashad of the
menites well I don't know what those uh
last two verses will have to do for your
your question but to answer your
question Moses didn't didn't even Cross
Jordan he stayed on the side of Jordan
before crossing the Jordan and he died
there okay and
uh Joshua brought the people brought the
Israelites over Jordan into the promised
land okay so let's go reads uh those
verses uh read let's go
to uh
chapter
31 and read verse one and two and then
we going to do chapter 32 after
that yeah stand that Deuteronomy
31 yeah stand that Deuteronomy and go to
31 read verse one and two and then we
going to go to 32 chapter 32 after
that goad Moses went and spake these
words unto all Israel and he said unto
them I am 120 years old this day I can
no more go out and come in also the Lord
have said unto me thou should not go
over this Joy uhuh now let's go to the
32nd chapter and read verse 48- 52 is as
quickly as you
can go ahead speaking to Moses that
selfs same day saying get thee up into
the mountains abam unto Mount Nebo which
is in the land of Moab that is over
against Jericho and behold the land of
Canaan which I give unto the children of
Israel for a possession and die in the
mou whether thou goest and be gathered
unto thy people as Aaron thy brother
died in Mount and was gathered
unto his people because he transgressed
against me among the children of Israel
at the water of mayabi cish in the
wilderness of sin because he s he
Sanctified me not in the midst of the
the children of Israel yet thou shall
see the land before thee but thou shall
not go there unto the land which I give
the children of
Israel okay so no Moses didn't go over
okay he died before he went over into
the promised land cross the Jordan
that's all I
got all right moving on to our next
question moving on
eatha asked for expan
in Jeremiah
30:
6-8 what is the time of Jacob's trouble
is this the Great Tribulation period and
they want you to explain verses 7
and8 all right let's go to Jeremiah
30 pick it up at that verse 6 and asking
for seven and eight and what is the time
of Jacob's trouble it's a terrible time
go ahead brother
Jeremiah 30 verse 6
yep as she now and see what a man doeth
travail with child wherefore do I see
every man with his hands on this lo as a
woman in travail and all faces are
turned into
pness but at last for that day is great
so that none is like it it is even the
time of Jacob's trouble he shall be
saved out of it but it shall come to
pass in that day said the Lord of H that
I will break his yoke from off thy neck
and will burst thy bonds and strangers
shall no more serve themselves of him
but they shall serve the Lord their God
and David their King whom I will raise
up unto
them therefore fear not fear thou not
that's good that's good brother guess
call
him here the first thing is he says H uh
uh you know when they ask the question
is it the Great tribulation yes it is a
Great Tribulation because he said that
there's going to be a time like and and
like no
other and we'll show you what that time
is called let's go to Matthew the 24th
chapter read vers 15 and Skip down and
read verse
21 when you she therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the Prophet stand in the Holy
Place whoo reth let him understand I
skip down to verse 21 for then there
shall be great tribulations just as was
not since the beginning of this world to
this time no nor ever shall
be I can't be but one time where where
they can't where there was nothing like
it before and nothing after so that is
the great
tribulations but it's talking about the
now at down that verse Now read that
verse uh uh uh uh seven and 8 again in
the
[Music]
uhi go back to Jer Jeremiah 30 yes yeah
at last for that day
is at last for that day is great so that
none is like it it is even the time of
Jacob's trouble but for he shall be
saved out of it for it shall come to
pass that day sayth the Lord of host
that I will break his yoke from off thy
neck and will burst thy bonds and
strangers shall no more serve themselves
of
him so that's that's when the Lord come
I go back in 24th chapter of St Matthews
and read verse 29 to
31 immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the son be darkened and
the moon shall not give her light and
the Stars shall fall from Heaven and the
powers of Heaven shall be shaken and
then shall appear the sign of the son of
man in heaven and then shall all the
tribes of the earth mourn and they shall
see the son of man coming in the Clouds
Of Heaven with power and great Glory he
shall send his angels with a great sound
of a trumpet and they shall gather
together his elect from the Four Winds
from one end of Heaven to the
other now that is when the Lord come he
going to bring Israel back so once the
Lord come he going to take down all the
nations then he going to send his Angel
to sound a trumpet and he going to start
together his people now let's go into
Isaiah 27 read verses 12 and
13 Isaiah 27
was that 12 and
13 yeah and it shall come to pass in
that day that the Lord shall beat off
the channels of the rivers into the
stream of Egypt and he shall be gathered
one by one oh ye children of
Israel this shall come to pass in that
day that the great trumpet shall be
blown and they shall come which were
ready to perish in the land of Assyria
and the alcaz in the land of Egypt and
shall Worship the Lord in the Holy
Mountain at
[Music]
Jerusalem now once and once that is that
mean the Lord is back in Jerusalem the
Lord is in charge of the earth and ain't
nobody going to press Israel anymore
through ass sure the Great Tribulation
the time of Jacob's trouble but
immediately after those tribulation the
Lord's going to bring trouble on the
world and then he going to send and and
deliver his people from all over the
world so ain't nobody else going to
exact no kind of punishment upon them
right
okay all right hope that answered your
question sister Deborah time is flying
because we having fun yes so the next
one is from me to4 you Jones as in amus
4 verse 13 and Amos 5 verse 8 and 18 in
regards to night and day I assume God is
stating Within These scriptures that the
day start at night is that correct all
right brother
Julius you got two out of
three your uh Amos 4 and 13 read it
quickly tedel Amos 4
and13 for Lo he that formed the
mountains and created the wind and
declared unto the man what is his
thought that maketh the morning darkness
and treadeth upon the high places of the
Earth the Lord the god of host is name
so the darkness the day start in
darkness read verse Amos 5 and8 go ahead
seek him that maketh the Seven Stars in
oron and turn the shadow of death in the
morning and maketh the day dark with
night that call for the Waters of the
sea and pour them out upon the face of
the Earth the Lord is his name he
showing you he showing you that the
evening and the morning make a day read
verse 18
this has this has nothing to do with
this right here is the day of the Lord
this has nothing to do with the daily
cycle the your everyday 24hour day read
it For unto you that desire the day of
the Lord to what end is it for you the
day of the Lord is dark is not and not
light now that's not talking about your
literal 24-hour day that is the time
when the Lord uh as we said earlier in
the program that represents the return
of the Lord
let's see when God starts his day
Genesis chapter
1 it's just like sisters and brothers
you work the third shift you work 11 to
7 or you work 12 to 8 whatever it is you
greet your co-workers at midnight but
you say good morning but it's dark
outside because the the darkness the the
day started in darkness Genesis 1 And1
go ahead tzel in the beginning God
created the heavens and the Earth and
the Earth will was without form and void
and darkness was upon the face of the
deep and the spirit of God moved upon
the face of the waters so the darkness
was already here before the day go ahead
and God said let there be light and
there was light uhhuh God saw the light
that it was good and God divided the
light from the darkness yes God called
the light day in the darkness he called
night right and the evening and the
morning were the first day notice the
evening and the morning Begins the day
but you got uh the light part of the day
and you got the darkness part of the day
but the day actually start in darkness
that's why he said the evening that's
absence of the
sun and the morning for the first day
that's all I got right all right thank
you for that brother sister Deborah
let's go to one more question okay uh
the last question yay motion animate
as was Caleb an Edomite that joined into
the tribe of Judah as an Israelite by
way of his
kenite father
jeffon
in Joshua 14 verse1 and Chronicles 4
verse
15 all right brother Jerome
no uh he he was a
Israelite of the tribe of Judah you know
but let's go read the those verses that
you
gave Joshua 14 and
one say it again Joshua uh 14 verse
okay and these are the countries which
the children of Israel inherit in the
land of Canaan which Eleazar the priest
and J the son of none and the heads of
the fathers of the tribes of the
children of Israel distribute for
inheritance to them and the other one
you gave was uh Chronicles 4 verse 15
yeah Chronicles 4 15 First
Chronicles yes First Chronicles
1 Chronicles
4:15 and the sons of Caleb the sons of
jeun IU Eli and Anam and the sons of Eli
even can yeah so now if you trace this
lineage of Caleb all the way up to the
first verse it'll let you know he come
out of Judah so go to the first
verse the sons of Judah farz hezron and
Ki and her and showall yeah you trace it
all the way down to the 15th verse that
you gave in the question he of he's of
Juda that's all I
got all right thank you for that brother
sister deorah time chat
9:01 9:01 we have ran out of time and
we'd like to thank everybody from all
around the world who joined us and sent
in those questions we enjoy taking part
in answering them but we ask if you
submitted a question we didn't have a
chance to get to it please don't
resubmit your question sister Deborah
take it put it in rotation and we will
deal with that question next Wednesday
and we also ask you that this Saturday
at 12:00 you can join us for our fourth
leg of black history which is titled the
priest of God to see who God chose out
of all the creation to be his priest so
you can join us at 520 West 138th Street
that's in Riverdale Illinois
60827 so until we all come together
again we ask you all to be safe be
blessed stay prayed up and may the Lord
have mercy on us all is brother tanzel
closes us out Our Father which are in
heaven Hallowed be thy name thy kingdom
come thy will be done in earth as it is
in heaven give us this day our daily
bread and forgive us of our has ask we
forgive our that to us and lead us not
into temptation but Deliver Us from Evil
for thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever in Jesus name we
pray amen amen good night